I am about to go live with Dr. Abidele Wach.
Ooh, I need to see his name to properly pronounce it.
But with a surgeon in Gaza.
And so that is what's about to do.
Thank you, Kimberney.
Thank you, Imuna.
So I'm just waiting for him to sign back on.
There we go.
It doesn't matter.
How are you?
Good.
Alhamdulillah.
I'm sorry, we don't have electricity here.
So the darkness.
What is the proper way to pronounce your name?
I'm Dr. Abidele Wach.
I'm a surgeon from North Carolina, Gaza Strip.
Now, during this war, I'm working at the Shifa Hospital, Indonesian Hospital, Camaritan Hospital.
And the last one now, last hospital, Al-Mamadani Hospital.
I want to talk about the situation here.
The situation now is very, very bad.
After the complete destroyed of Al-Shifa Hospital, now we don't have any medical health care here in North Gaza Strip.
Now, just Al-Mamadani Hospital that covers all North Gaza Strip.
Al-Mamadani Hospital, it's a small hospital, a private clinic, maybe a private clinic.
At Al-Mamadani Hospital, we don't have anything inside this hospital, just two operation rooms, we don't have ICU beds, we don't have the emergency department.
Every day, we receive a lot of wounded, we receive all this wounded on the ground, we don't have beds inside this hospital, we don't have medical supply, we don't have any healthy food or water for this wounded.
So, the situation here is very, very bad, we don't have medical staff, all the medical staff left us and went to the south or outside Gaza.
Now, at the north, we have just three general surgeons, I'm one of them, so the situation here is very, very bad.
We are exhausted here, we don't have anything, we don't have any meaning of life here, nothing.
I think for those who are listening, and myself included, we are so, we feel so, so much pain for what you're experiencing and for the ways in which the world has stood in the way of providing for you and your people.
So, and I know many of us are continuously trying our best to figure out how to, to figure out how to change that and how to get there, get an immediate ceasefire, how to get these, you know, the crossings open to allow aid in.
I mean, what we're seeing now in Israel is, it seems like they are getting closer and closer to just the government no longer being able to sustain, which I think does have some, you know, some positive things to it.
But I just, I just, I just always feel, I just always feel, I feel, I just feel so terrible not being able to tell you that we can help because I don't know what to do.
But I know people, you know, you should follow Dr. Abdelwahab and, you know, we're still trying to donate.
Is there, is there any aid that comes through even if it is not through the typical means?
At the North, since a few days, we, some of the food aids and medical supply aids arrived to us, but a small amount, not enough.
And the North has stood now, more than half a million.
So what arrived to us, not enough for our people.
The situation here is very, very bad.
Really now, I want to evacuate my family outside Gaza.
In December, I have lost, our home was bumping and I have lost 31 of my family members.
Oh my God.
I have now just 20 of my family members.
I want to evacuate my family outside Gaza for searching for safety.
I want to stay here at the North Gaza Strip.
I want to stay here to help our people and wounded.
But really, I want to evacuate my family outside Gaza.
So I make a, create a link of GoFundMe to evacuate my, to help me to evacuate my family outside Gaza.
But I will stay here, inshaAllah.
In terms of, I saw that people are starting to come back to Northern Gaza.
Is that true?
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
What's happened, our people from the South coming to the North, trying to arrive from the IDF,
but the IDF, bumping the people and gunshot all the people, trying to reach to us at the North Gaza Strip.
No one arrived to us.
How are you performing these surgeries with no anesthesia?
What?
Surgery?
I mean, how are patients able to heal with no food?
They're not.
Really, inside our hospital, we don't have any medical supply.
Maybe perform the operation without analgesia, without sedation, and sometimes food.
All the patients, all our patients, all the people on North Gaza Strip now,
loss of weight.
We don't have any healthy food in here.
We don't have any medical supply, all the medical supply running out.
Really here, we lost all the meaning of life here.
I'm, you know, I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm really at a loss for words.
I think for so many of us, we are just consistently just at a loss for words in order to try to pay
regard to what's going on, but we don't know what to do.
And, um, is there, I guess what I would like to know is, what, what can we do?
I know you wanted to come on this live and I want to, of course, just amplify your story and,
and, uh, you know, give continuously give voice to Palestinians because I mean,
there's so many other people talking, um, I would love to hear though, what you would
like to ask of the people here that are watching from safety.
I can't hear what.
I'd like to know, you know, what would you like to ask of these people here that are
watching, you know, from the safety of their own homes?
How can they be helpful?
How can they help the people in the North?
Yeah.
Just, uh, to bring for the, uh, people here, maybe donation, maybe to anything for support us.
I will be, the people can't do any things really, uh, the decision, uh, related to the, uh, IDF,
not to the people here.
Well, I can promise you that we won't stop.
We will not stop.
They thought that we would stop.
They thought that people would be over this.
They thought they could distract us with all types of nonsense.
They thought they could, you know, scare us into the normal fear of antisemitism.
And we won't, we will not stop and we'll continue to fight and raise our voices and
disrupt and force these people to have to back down.
I mean, that is the goal of so many people more than ever, I would say, in the fight
for Palestinian freedom.
And all I can do is ask you to, you know, hold, continue to hold on because there's,
there's so many people out here that love you, even though we don't know you, that love the
Palestinian people that understand and believe in what is right and understand and believe
in ways that they didn't know before.
So many people didn't know.
They did not know.
And now so many people are waking up.
And I really do believe that we are closer to a Palestinian liberation than ever in history.
And that is where that prayer can be right, can be risen from.
That is where this vibration can be risen from.
We stand with you.
We really do.
People are asking, how can they donate to you?
Do you have a GoFundMe or anywhere they can donate?
Yeah.
I have GoFundMe.
I'm credited to GoFundMe.
Is it on your page?
Yeah.
On my bio.
Okay, so you all, I have, I have, um, Dr. Abd al-Wahhab's, uh, his, his app right here,
so you can go to his page and donate.
I know you are trying to get your, your family out.
And you want, you want to stay.
And I want to stay here to help other people, help the wounded.
I will never lift Gaza, especially in North, the Gaza Strip.
I want to stay here.
What's the status of all Shifa now?
They, to, to my understanding, they've completely, um.
Shifa Hospital now really completely destroyed.
All the, all the building completely destroyed, uh, and building, uh, now, uh, for removal,
Shifa Hospital, uh, need built, uh, from new, uh, all the building inside the Shifa Hospital
really completely destroyed.
With the attack, uh, uh, uh, on Sunday after midnight to Shifa Hospital, uh, I'm, uh, working
at the Shifa at this night.
Uh, uh, after midnight suddenly gunshot inside our hospital.
Uh, and, uh, uh, uh, suddenly bombing around us, heavy bombing.
Uh, uh, some of people, uh, can escape from the hospital, uh, and one of them included, uh,
the people can escape from the hospital in the beginning of the attacks of the hospital.
After that, all the medical staff, some of the medical staff was arrested and other parts
of the medical staff were released to the house.
So now we don't have any medical staff.
From the beginning of the war, part of the medical staff also left us and went to the
house all outside Gaza.
Now we have just three general surgeons, just two orthopedic surgeons, just one vascular
surgeon.
We don't have any neurosurgeon, any neurosurgeon.
A lot of specialties, we don't have any surgeons here.
So some of the people, some of the wounded arrived to us.
We don't know what we are doing for this wounded, just stay helpless, really.
I'm sorry.
That's our situation here.
Every day the situation gets worse, so really, we have the meaning of life here.
You know, I don't know if these words matter, but you continuing to think of the safety
of your family, you continuing to work and use your God's gift for your people is the epitome
of the meaning of life.
Yeah.
And it is unconscionable that other people are putting you in this situation.
You know, this isn't a natural disaster.
This is an unnatural disaster.
But what you're doing is honorable, it is noble, and you will be always provided for by Allah.
Yeah.
And you know that.
And it really is a tragedy that we cannot seem to undo the evil of these people in the
time that we want to.
But all we can really do is try our best to shift their axis of evil, and we will continue
to do that in any way that we can.
And I also know that I really do believe that liberation for Palestine is soon.
And I know that the fall of America is also soon.
I hope that.
I hope the war will end.
Really, at the beginning of the war, we don't leave our Gaza city, but after it was home, our
home was bombed, and I lost 31 of my family members, now I won't evacuate my family outside
Gaza.
I don't want to lose any more from my family.
I want to evacuate the Gaza, looking for safety.
But I want to stay here, at the north.
If I was arrested or died, I will stay here.
I understand.
And, you know, I can't see your face here, but I'm looking at your page so I can see your
face, and I see how young you are.
And you are speaking with the wisdom and the heart of an elder and of an old soul.
And I wish there was something, I wish you were at a cafe.
But what we are going to do is, you know, your GoFundMe is here on your page.
So everybody who's watching, you can help Dr. Abdel Wahab get his family out of Gaza.
I will contribute as well.
And we will continue to contribute in a myriad of ways, through money, through time, through
our resources, through boycott, through disruption, with our bodies, all the above.
And we understand.
And I will continue to raise the voices of individuals like yourself and of the Palestinian
people, because everyone needs to understand that your struggle is everyone's struggle.
It is.
Thank you.
Thank you for everything.
Thank you, Amanda.
Thank you.
And I appreciate you.
I know it took a little bit because I had to finish my other job.
But I'm glad that we were able to speak.
And I will continue to check on you.
And now follow me.
Okay.
Say one more time.
Follow me now.
I'm following you, Dr. Abdel Wahab.
I'm following you right now.
Follow.
Okay.
I'm waiting.
Please.
I'm following you.
Thank you.
Salaam.